Speaker 1: Republicans just voted to push the country toward a government shutdown. Let me explain. Just a little while ago, I cast two votes in the United States Senate. One was against the one-way, completely partisan Republican budget. The other was a proposal that we have made to Republicans in the Senate. I voted for that proposal to keep the government
open.
Speaker 1: Here's the problem: Senate Republicans say they want a bipartisan budget agreement. But they're not calling the shots. Donald Trump is calling all the shots because Republicans in the House and the Senate, at the end of the day, they have contracted out their votes and their responsibilities to Donald Trump. I am not going to write a blank check
to a
Speaker 1: lawless president.
We
Speaker 1: need guardrails, we need safeguards, because right now the president is refusing to spend funds that we've invested in Americans' healthcare at NIH and other places. And he's refusing to spend monies for public safety through FEMA. So that's why the democratic proposal that I voted
for
Speaker 1: includes those guardrails, but it also includes something else. It addresses some of the big critical healthcare issues we're facing in this country. Because Republicans have left a ticking time bomb on important healthcare for America. Specifically, at the end of this year, the premium tax credits for people on the Affordable Care Act will
go away.
Speaker 1: That will immediately mean millions of Americans will lose access to health insurance.
but
Speaker 1: it actually will impact everybody in a harmful way because insurance rates and premiums are going to go up across the board. So we want to turn off this ticking time bomb so it doesn't blow up access to healthcare for America. That's the proposal we put forward, but Donald Trump, he's taken the position that he's king and it's his way
or
Speaker 1: nothing. And sadly, Republicans are going along. They are clearly heading toward a government shutdown for this country. And there's a way to avoid it through bipartisanship, but that requires people to come together for the good of the country.